Camila Aparicio

Front-End Web Developer

Portfolio: www.camilaaparicio.com
Email: camilaaparicio@hotmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/camilaaparicio

Github: github.com/camiaparicio

I am a front-end web developer with a passion for building responsive, accessible and engaging websites. My past experiences have cultivated my strong communication and problem solving skills. I have a constant desire and eagerness to keep learning and broadening my knowledge in web development.

Languages: English & Spanish

Skills

HTML5 · CSS3 · SCSS · JavaScript · jQuery · APIs · ReactJS · Responsive
Design · Content Management System
(Kentico) · Browser Testing · Git /
GitHub · Command Line · Web
Accessibility - WCAG 2.0 & AODA · Pair
Programing · Jira · Figma · Wireframes &
Mockups · Adobe Photoshop

Education

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp Certificate @ Juno College of Technology 2021

Honours Bachelor of Applied Science in Social Work @ University of Guelph-Humber

2012-2016

Experience

UI Web Developer @ Canadian Red Cross

March 2022 - Present | Maternity Leave Cover

- Develop and maintain front-end web pages with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Works in an Agile environment using Jira project management.
- Collaborates closely with the Design and Marketing teams creating mock-ups for updated, modern, accessible UI web parts and pages.
- Experience with accessibility audit reports using tools to ensure AODA standards and WCAG 2.0 guidelines for redcross.ca, and for other Red Cross teams were being met.

Pension Technician @ LifeWorks / formerly Morneau Shepell

2019 - 2022

- Calculated and issued benefit payments in accordance with plan rules and legislation.
- Answered queries from clients, plan members and trustees, providing relevant information and appropriate follow-up.

Projects

CrossPlay @ Canadian Red Cross

www.redcross.ca/crossplay/

Developed using Kentico CMS, this custom site is used for gamers to support the CRC fundraising. Worked on the design for mobile and desktop views. Collaborated with design and full-stack developer to build this site.

Meme in a Giffy @ Juno College Github Repo / Live Site

A group-programmed React application that allows users to generate their own memes by inputting text and saving their favourite results by using Firebase.